<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on ForensicXlab</title>
    <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on ForensicXlab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 18:03:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.forensicxlab.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>🔦 Video Games Forensics : Steam </title>
      <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/steam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 18:03:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/steam/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Link to heading Video games have become an integral part of our culture, providing entertainment and social opportunities. Unfortunately, criminals have also begun to take advantage of modern video games and their ever-growing capabilities to conduct illegal activities. Organized crime, hate spread, and pedophilia have been documented occurring within games, opening up the potential to a world of cybercrime.
Digital forensics on the Steam application can be especially useful for law enforcement in tracking down and prosecuting these cybercriminals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📦 Volatility3 Linux Plugin : Inodes</title>
      <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/inodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 21:11:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/inodes/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Link to heading The filesystem is one of the most basic and important concepts in UNIX/Linux. This concept is working around the idea that “everything is a file”, meaning that the hardware, regular files, directories, sockets, kernel data structures, process communications etc are represented as files with their own types. On a filesystem, a file (whatever its type) is assigned with a number called an &amp;ldquo;inode&amp;rdquo;. An inode is an interface between the blocks on the filesystem and the file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
