<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Memory Forensics on ForensicXlab</title>
    <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/tags/memory-forensics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Memory Forensics on ForensicXlab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 21:03:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.forensicxlab.com/tags/memory-forensics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>📦 Volatility3 Windows Plugin : KeePass</title>
      <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/keepass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 21:03:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/keepass/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Link to heading On May 1st, 2023, vdhoney1 raised concerns about an issue found on KeePass 2.X 2 where he was able to reconstruct the master password. A POC 3 was later released by the researcher in dotnet, and another in python3 4. Today we will describe the vulnerability and see how we can create a volatility3 plugin to help forensics investigators retrieve passwords.
Vulnerability description Link to heading The vulnerability (CVE-2023-32784 5) reside in the basic KeePass version 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📦 Volatility3 Windows Plugin : AnyDesk</title>
      <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/anydesk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 16:06:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/anydesk/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Link to heading When performing incident response, the adversary often uses legitimate remote access software as an interactive command and control channel. AnyDesk1 is one of those software being extensively used as a sublayer of persistence by threat actors or access other servers in the environment via RDP2.
The latter has been often encountered in the wild in the past years as a preferred tool leveraged by known threat actors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📦 Volatility3 Linux Plugin : Inodes</title>
      <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/inodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 21:11:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/inodes/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Link to heading The filesystem is one of the most basic and important concepts in UNIX/Linux. This concept is working around the idea that “everything is a file”, meaning that the hardware, regular files, directories, sockets, kernel data structures, process communications etc are represented as files with their own types. On a filesystem, a file (whatever its type) is assigned with a number called an &amp;ldquo;inode&amp;rdquo;. An inode is an interface between the blocks on the filesystem and the file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📦 Volatility3 Windows Plugin : Prefetch</title>
      <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/prefetch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 17:24:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/prefetch/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Link to heading Windows prefetch files are temporary files stored in the %SystemRoot%\System\Prefetch folder. This memory management feature is keeping track of the frequently running applications on a given system. We can extract some data from those files in order to get useful information for a digital forensic investigation. In this blog article, I will explain how we can use memory forensic to extract prefetch files, parse them and create in the end a volatility3 plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🖋 Cyberdefenders - Writeup : Brave</title>
      <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/cyberdefenders_brave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 17:17:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/cyberdefenders_brave/</guid>
      <description>This writeup is covering the cyberdefenders.org challenge named &amp;ldquo;Brave&amp;rdquo;. Today we are going to solve this challenge using the VolWeb memory analysis platform.
Scenario Link to heading A memory image was taken from a seized Windows machine. Analyze the image and answer the provided questions.
Analysis creation Link to heading After firing up your instance of VolWeb, login to the platform, create a new Windows investigation and upload the challenge memory image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📘 Using Volatility3 as a library</title>
      <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/vol_as_lib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 16:42:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/vol_as_lib/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Link to heading Being interested in memory forensic for a while now, I have learned a lot about the volatility3 framework. In this article, we will go through how you can use the framework&amp;rsquo;s libraries to automate your memory analysis tasks and directly exploit the results. I will assume in this article that the reader has a basic understanding of how volatility3 is exploiting memory to extract evidence. If you want to learn more about volatility3, you can check the links in the &amp;ldquo;References&amp;rdquo; section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📄 Volatility3 - ISF for MacOs</title>
      <link>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/macos_isf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 16:14:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.forensicxlab.com/posts/macos_isf/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Link to heading Being interested in memory forensic for a while now I have learned a lot about the Volatility framework. This article will introduce volatility3 core components and focus on kernel symbols. Next, I will explain the steps I took to generate a lot of MacOs SymbolTables. Finally you will be able to retrieve those SymbolsTables directly from github. The final goal is to create a public repository like windows to automatically identify mac os system version and directly download the associated SymbolTables.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
